Partner up!
Pokémon Detective Pikachu is a action, adventure,
fantasy film directed by Rob Letterman.
In a world where people collect pocket-size monsters (Pokémon) to do battle, a boy
comes across an intelligent monster who seeks to be a detective.
Detective Pikachu (voice), played by Ryan Reynolds.
Tim Goodman, played by Justice Smith.
Lucy Stevens, played by Kathryn Newton.
Ms. Norman, played by Suki Waterhouse.
Sebastian, played by Omar Chaparro.
Roger Clifford, played by Chris Geere.
Pokémon Detective Pikachu is a 2019 fantasy comedy film and the
first live-action film based on the Pokémon franchise.
It is a loose adaptation of the 2016 video game Detective Pikachu.
Directed by Rob Letterman, who co-wrote it with Dan Hernandez, Benji Samit, and Derek Connolly, the film stars Ryan Reynolds as the voice and motion capture
of Pikachu, with Justice Smith, Kathryn Newton, Suki Waterhouse, Omar Chaparro, Chris Geere, Ken Watanabe and Bill Nighy in live-action roles.
The plot follows Detective Pikachu and his partner Tim Goodman as they attempt
to solve the mysterious disappearance of Tim's father, Harry.
Filming took place from January to May 2018 in Colorado, England, and Scotland.
Detective Pikachu was released in Japan on May 3, 2019, and in
the United States on May 10, by Warner Bros.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $433 million against a $150
million budget, becoming the second-highest grossing video game film adaptation at the time.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of amnesia, detective, car
crash, whodunit, based on video game.
The tone is dark.